Chopper's on its way!
헬기가 오고 있대!
Rescue says they're about 20 minutes out!
20분이면 도착한다는데?
He doesn't have 20 minutes!
We got to get him now!
20분까지 못 버텨
당장 구조해야 해!
Okay, I'll rig up and join you!
지지대를 만들어서 잡아당길게
[Breathing heavily]
[Speaking Spanish] Huh?
선생님이 왔어
상태 좀 보자
선생님 이름은 티시야
Yo soy un doctor. Me llamo T.C.
좋지 않군
[Exhales]
[Groans]
여길 다쳤구나
Okay. He's in shock.
He's got an open wound.
쇼크 상태에 빠졌어
개방성 상처에다
이중골절이고
Tib-Fib fracture. He needs
to get out of here ASAP.
당장 구조해야 돼
I'll give you a signal to pull us up.
신호를 주면 잡아당기고
And tell the chopper to get his ass here.
조종사한테 꽁지 빠지게
오라고 연락해
All right, uh, use this
cream three times a day,
하루 세 번씩
꼬박 연고를 바르시면
- 발진은 감쪽같이 사라질 거예요
- 알겠습니다
- and the rash will clear right up, okay?
- Okay.
'오후 7시 31분'
국가를 위한 노고에 감사드립니다
Hey, and thank you for your
service to this country.
- 감사합니다
- 안녕히 가세요
- Thank you.
- Yeah. [Alert chimes]
커밍스 선생님께 전화 왔습니다
Woman on P.A.: Telephone for Dr. Cummings.
커밍스 선생님을 찾습니다
Paging Dr. Cummings.
Hello, this is Dr. C... oh, gross!
안녕하세요, 커밍스...
으익, 뭐야!
- [Laughter]
- Kenny!
케니!
Wherever you are, you're dead!
잡히면 가만 안 둬요!
이 정도면 건드린 사람도 이상해
I wouldn't take that crap if I were you.
15분 정도 안정을
취하게 하시고
Okay, give him another 15 minutes rest
항생제 처방한 뒤
퇴원시키세요
then send him home with the antibiotics.
- 몰리, 수고해요
- 별 말씀을요
- Thanks, Mollie.
- You're welcome.
- Hey, how'd it go?
- Check this out. Night shift special.
- 할 만해?
- 여기 봐. 이 맛에 한다니까
Two guys fought a duel with
nail guns outside of the Alamo.
알라모 밖에서 두 남자가
네일건으로 싸웠는데
- [Beep]
- And the first guy missed, second guy didn't.
한 쪽은 빗나갔지만
다른 쪽은 명중했어
- Well, I hope he already had kids.
- Mm-hmm.
- 애는 미리 낳아뒀길 바라
- 그러게
- Right.
- No, please, stop! I...
나 좀 살려줘요, 제발...
I-I don't know how you
handled all this paperwork
그동안 이 서류들을
어떻게 처리했어?
- when you were in charge.
- I do not miss that part of the job.
서류작업만 빼면
그 일도 할 만한데
Jordan, I need you! Male
and female, both 40s.
조든, 도와줘!
40대 부부 환자야
Status post-penetrating rebar injury
오토바이를 타다
쇠막대가 관통했어
- while riding a motorcycle.
- Okay. Trauma 1.
외상실 1번으로 이송해
Uh... rebar? What... flew off
the back of a truck on 410.
- 쇠막대가... 어쩌다가?
- 적재물 사고야
Male with a through-and-through
skull injury.
두개골 관통상을 입은
남성 환자는
영문은 모르겠지만 멀쩡한데
G.C.S. of
4-6-5, somehow.
Female with a penetrating throat injury.
목에 관통상을 입은
여성 환자는
She's tachy. B.P. of 90 systolic.
빈맥이 있고
혈압은 90이야
So far her sats are holding.
산소포화도는 변함이 없고
What's with the splint?
웬 부목이에요?
Gross abnormality of the distal radius
떨어지면서 요골 원위부에
from the fall. It's closed.
폐쇄 골절이 있었어요
Okay, this is gonna need sutures!
여긴 봉합이 필요하겠어
All right, I'm on it. All right,
그건 내가 맡을게
외상과에 협진 요청해주세요!
let's get trauma down
here for a consult ASAP.
Dr. Cummings is in surgery.
커밍스 선생님은
수술방에 들어가서
I got to call in Dr. Chavez,
the new night surgeon.
차베스 선생님을 부를게요
새로 오셨어요
Hell of a first shift for him.
첫날부터 고생이겠네
Thank you. Really could've
used T.C. on this one.
- 감사해요
- 티시가 딱 제격인데
He never should have been suspended.
선배한테 정직 처분을
내리신 일이나
You don't take a doc like
that out of the E.R. agreed.
인원을 외부에서
수혈한 건 너무하셨어요
별수 없잖아
티시도 자리에 없고
But you know T.C. can't
stop him from working.
Ah... hold on! He's choking.
잠깐만 멈춰!
애가 숨을 못 쉬어
- [Gasping, raspy breathing]
- Okay, I got you. Come on.
잡고 있으니 안심해
뭔가 걸린 것 같은데 기침해봐
You got something in there. Cough. Hmm?
[Speaking Spanish] Hey! What's going on?
밑에 무슨 일이야?
He's got partial airway occlusion!
부분 기도폐쇄야!
If we take him up any further,
his airway's gonna block!
계속 잡아당기면
기도가 막힐거야
I need you! He's completely obstructed!
도와줘, 기도가
완전히 막혔어!
[Gasping]
- [Gasping]
- Coming down with your med kit!
장비 들고 내려갈게!
[Spits]
[Grunting]
젠장
Son of a bitch.
솜뭉치를 삼켰던 게
목을 틀어막았어
He's got cotton balls
stuck down his throat.
- Hand me a j-wire.
- Cotton balls?
- 유도철사 좀 꺼내줘
- 솜뭉치?
Yeah. Some coyotes across the borders,
응, 난민 밀수업자 중에선
국경을 통과할 때
솜뭉치에 주스를 적혀서
they soak cotton balls
in juice to feed the kids
애들에게 음식 대신 먹이거든
instead of food.
But they don't digest, so they choke easy.
소화가 안되다 보니
쉽게 질식하지
Come on, get in there. Get in there.
좀 들어가라
- [Choking]
- He's turning blue.
청색증이 일어나
- 할 줄 아는 거야?
- 뭐로 보고
- You got this?
- Yeah.
유도철사를 거꾸로 넣어
기도를 뚫으면 돼
I need to clear his airway
with the retrograde j-wire.
- [Coughing]
- Ah, there we go. There we go.
됐구나, 됐어
Hang in there. Hang in there.
조금만 버티렴
There we go. Yes!
빼냈어, 잘 버텼어!
You're all good. Good job, buddy, come on.
수고했어
어서 올라가자
Yeah, welcome back.
꼬마야, 살아서 다행이다
Okay, let's make our way back up.
다시 올라가 볼까?
[Heavy breathing] Nice and slowly.
조심스럽게 가자고
Okay. Up...
- [Labored breathing]
- [Beeping]
환자분, 움직이시면 안 돼요!
Sir, hold still! Don't
even move an inch, okay?
부인께선 진통제를
맞고 계세요
Your wife's being sedated on pain medicine.
검사를 진행하려면
의식을 유지해야 되니
We need to keep you lucid
to follow your neuro exams,
so we can't give you
any pain meds right now.
당장은 진통제를 못 드려요
- 안 아파요!
- 손목도 안 아프세요?
- I don't feel any pain.
- None? What about your wrist?
I don't care about my wrists!
지금 손목이 문제예요?
This is all my fault!
She hates the motorcycle.
내가 죽일 놈이에요!
오토바이라면 질색을 하는
사람을 데리고...
- I talked her...
- Sir, you need to be calm.
환자분, 진정하세요
You keep moving around,
you're gonna endanger
계속 움직이시면
두 분 다 위험해져요
- both of you, okay?
- [Breathing heavily] Okay.
알겠습니다
Okay, I'm done here. Let's get some...
여긴 마무리했으니까...
- dressing on it.
- Topher: Dr. Chavez, I presume.
- 드레싱만 하면 돼
- 차베스 선생님입니까?
- 조이라고 부르세요
- 선생님, 저한테 주세요
- Joey.
- I can take that, Doctor.
Scott will be down as soon as he can.
스캇 선생님도
되는 대로 오시겠대요
He's still elbows deep
in a splenectomy case.
비장 절제 수술에
매달려 계시거든요
선생님들, 잠시만요
현재 상황이 어떻습니까?
Everybody, huddle up. Let's
get some information here.
We need to get this helmet
off. Are they both medicated?
헬멧을 제거할 건데
둘 다 진통제를 맞았죠?
The wife is. The husband is
conscious but reporting no pain.
부인만 놨어요, 남편은 의식이
있는데 통증을 못 느끼거든요
- Really?
- But he is pretty freaked out.
- 정말입니까?
- 대신 겁을 먹었습니다
All right, I'm gonna work
on getting the helmet off.
본격적으로 헬멧을
제거해봅시다
You guys complete the
secondary survey on the wife.
그동안 여러분들은
부인 상태 좀 확인해주세요
- All right? Let's roll.
- You guys okay here? I'm getting paged.
- 본격적으로 해볼까요?
- 두 사람이 맡아줄래? 호출이 왔네
- Yeah, we got this.
- Uh, what's the patient's name?
- 저희가 맡겠습니다
- 환자분 성함이 뭐랬죠?
- Craig.
- 크레이그요
- 크레이그
Mind if I borrow this? Thanks.
잠시만 빌릴게요, 감사합니다
All right, Craig. You do yoga?
안녕하세요, 크레이그 씨
요가하시나요?
- Uh, n-no.
- No?
- 안 하는데요
- 안 하세요?
All right. Well, you're
going to learn right now.
상관없어요
지금 배우면 되죠
- How's that sound?
- Uh... Mm...
- 괜찮죠?
- 그게... 그러니까...
All right, just follow my pen here.
제 볼펜을 쫓아와 보시겠어요?
Good job, Craig.
잘하셨어요
Now, I want you to focus on your breathing.
지금은 호흡법을 알려드릴게요
Sound of the saw can be a bit unnerving,
톱질 소리가 신경을
곤두서게 만들텐데
and breath is the bridge
between the mind and the body.
몸과 마음은 숨결을 통해
교감한다고 하죠
The longer you exhale, the
more relaxed you're going to be.
숨을 모아 길게 내뱉으면
마음이 더 차분해진답니다
Can you do that?
하실 수 있죠?
I'll try.
해볼게요
Drill, please. Thank you.
드릴 좀 주시겠어요?
Namaste, everybody.
나마스떼
[Drill whirring]
So, the new night surgeon...
Chavez... what's he like?
새로 들어왔다는
차베스 선생은 어때요?
사람이 앞서간다고 할까?
Very Dr. Granola.
너무 접촉이 잦더라니까
A little too touchy-feely for my taste.
[Singsongy] Oh, God, I forgot
it's Ragosa's first night back.
참, 오늘 라고사 실장님이
복귀하시는 날이었지
그러게, 혹이 하나 추가됐군
That's just what I need.
Another pain in my ass.
좋은 하루입니다
Evening, Gentlemen.
몰리도 있고
선생까지 있었네요?
Mollie. Topher!
Ha ha! [Inhales sharply]
오래간만이에요!
Mm! Good to have you back!
Hmm. How's the wife and kids?
아내분과 애들은 잘 지내요?
- 예, 잘 지내죠
- 다행이네요
- Good. They're good.
- Good.
[Clears throat] Good, good. Drew.
좋은 날만 가득해야죠
드류, 릭은 어때요?
How's Rick?
I hear you guys moved in together, right?
같이 산다고 들었는데?
He's doing as well as could be expected.
그런대로 잘 적응하고 있습니다
되는대로 의수를
빨리 달 겁니다
Should get his prosthetic leg any week.
You tell him to never give up hope.
좌절할 때마다
응원 해준다면서요
I didn't,
나도 그렇고
and this guy right here didn't, either.
여기 선생님도
그래본 적이 없는데
- Isn't that right, Topher?
- Yeah.
- 아니에요, 선생님?
- 맞아요
- Everything good with you?
- Yeah. Couldn't be better.
- 괜찮으신거 맞아요?
- 날아갈 것 같습니다
You survive a tumor, cheat death,
암에서 기적적으로
살아남아 봐요
everything else seems like small potatoes.
세상만사가 하찮게 보인답니다
- [Chuckles]
- We dodged a bullet, Topher.
우리 둘 한테는
시련이 빗겨나갔네요
Mm. Well, you didn't,
아, 선생은 아니지
- but you get my metaphor, right?
- Yeah.
- 무슨 얘기인지는 알죠?
- 이해했습니다
- We're survivors.
- I get it.
- 기어코 살아남았잖아요
- 그렇죠
- [Siren wailing in distance]
- Anyway...
[Sighs] First day back, lots to do.
그나저나...
복귀 첫날부터
할 일이 태산이군요
- See you boys around.
- Okay.
- 그럼 또 봅시다
- 가세요
Okay, that was weird, right?
무섭게 왜 저래?
I don't know who that was.
완전 딴사람 같네요
Uh... hey! Hey! I need a trauma room.
토퍼, 드류!
외상실 하나 잡아줘
- Oh... trauma 3!
- Okay.
- 3번으로 가!
- 알았어
Found this little guy in the wild,
황무지에서 구조했는데
probably abandoned by a coyote,
밀수업자가 버린 걸로 보여
with an open tibia fracture,
개방성 경골 골절에
an infected leg wound,
and severe dehydration.
다리 상처는 감염이 진행됐고
탈수도 심각해
He's gotten 40cc per kilogram bolus
멸균된 골내 도관으로
체중 1kg당 40cc씩
through a sterile I.O. line.
수액 투여해줘
Oh, come on. Send off a C.B.C.,
빨리 주세요
CBC, CMP 검사도 진행하고
a C.M.P., and get Ortho here ASAP.
정형외과 당직의도
불러주시고요
Here we go, here we go...
혈관이 어딨니...
- Tee, I hate to break it to you...
- All right, I'll draw the blood.
- 티, 산통 깨서 미안한데
- 채혈하겠습니다
But technically you're still suspended.
엄밀히 아직 정직 상태거든
Right. Sorry. Kenny,
Dr. Zia is gonna ask you
깜빡했네
케니, 지아 선생님께서
to start Ancef and Gent prophylaxis
개방성 골절 치료 및
상처 감염 예방 차원에서
for the open fracture
and the wound infection.
세파스포린과 겐타마이신
투여 하랍신다
Got it.
명을 받들죠
Dr. Zia's also gonna tell
you that Dr. Callahan,
그 지아 선생이
캘러한 선생은
although a brilliant doctor,
has been a pain in his ass
뛰어난 의사긴 한데
처음부터 쭉
골칫덩어리랍신다
since the day they met.
Yeah, but you still love me, huh? [Kisses]
얼씨구, 그래서 싫어?
I'm gonna slowly take this off of you.
헬멧을 천천히 분리하겠습니다
Okay, the bar is stable for now.
쇠막대도 변동이 없습니다
All right.
출발은 좋고
How you doing, Craig? You feeling any pain?
크레이그 씨, 지금도
통증이 없으세요?
괜찮습니다, 당신은 어때?
It's fine. Mary, how are you doing?
- 부인께서도 상태가 좋습니다
- 손잡아도 될까요?
- She's good. She's resting.
- Can I hold her hand?
물론이죠
Of course.
[Sighs]
Surgery took a lot longer than expected.
수술이 예상보다 오래 걸렸어
- 크리스타, 현재 상황은?
- 남성 환자는 손목 골절을 처치했고
- What do we got here, Krista?
- A reduced wrist fracture on the man,
여성 환자는
무릎 열상을 봉합했습니다
a sutured knee lac on the woman,
저 쇠막대가 큰 걸림돌입니다
and a large piece of rebar
causing all types of problems.
환자를 살리면서
양쪽으로 분리하는
So what we need to do is separate the two
- without killing them.
- I don't want to cut them apart
- 방향으로 가야 합니다
- 함부로 자르진 않을 거야
어디가 어떻게
손상을 입을지 모르는데
without seeing what
structures may be damaged.
There's no way we can fit
them in the C.T. like that.
CT에 집어넣을 방법은 없고
양쪽 끝을 자르면
될 것 같은데...
Well, what if we cut it
at both ends? Maybe...
조든 선생, 여기서부턴
외과 소임입니다
We'll handle it from here, Jordan.
This a surgical case now.
You can go back to the E.R.
응급실로 돌아가 보세요
Okay.
그럴게
도움 필요하면 불러
Let me know if you need anything.
All right, we're gonna clear
the bottom half of this helmet.
우선 헬멧의 남은 절반을
제거할 겁니다
Let's be ready to stabilize his head.
머리 고정해주세요
Joey: On my count, all right?
[Alert chimes] Woman on
P.A: Dr. Zia to trauma 1.
외상실 1번에서
지아 선생님을 찾습니다
- Hey. Jordy, check this out...
- Hey.
- 조디, 이것 좀 봐...
- 여깄었네
과거를 공유하는 중이야
For throwback Thursday.
What you got? Oh, wow!
뭔데... 어머!
- Right?
- Sophomore year?
- 죽이지?
- 2학년 때였나?
- Mm-hmm.
- Man, we were so into the Spice Girls.
- 아마도
- 한창 스파이스 걸스 좋아했지
Uh, uh, still into the Spice Girls.
난 지금도 좋아하는데?
- That's right.
- So, uh, Scott still being a dick to you?
- 그랬지 참
- 스캇이 아직도 심술 맞게 굴어?
Yeah. He's acting like...
계속 그런다, 뭐랄까...
Like he moved down here and you dumped him
기껏 내려와 줬더니 자길 차고
to get back with T.C.?
티시한테 갈 사람 취급해?
- Mm?
- Okay, I am not back together with T.C.
- 맞지?
- 보긴 잘 봤는데, 안 합쳐
and it is way more complicated than that.
복잡한 사정이 있어
Complicated, T.C. [Chuckles] No way.
티시와 복잡함?
전혀 안 어울리는데
Well, it's better that
he's complicated than...
몰라서 그래
복잡한 게 낫지...
What, boring?
아니면 지루해?
Our safest option without a scan
CT없이 가장 안전한 방법은
최대한 환자분과 가깝게
쇠막대를 자르는 겁니다
is to cut the rebar as
close to you as possible,
쇠막대 하중이
환자분 쪽으로
and that will keep the weight of the bar
쏠리는 걸 차단할 수 있습니다
from shifting toward your side.
그러면 메리 쪽으로
쏠린다는 소리잖아요?
So does that mean it shifts to her side?
그러면... 메리는
어떻게 되는 겁니까?
Wait... is it gonna be bad for Mary?
호흡곤란과 더불어 성대에도
There's potential respiratory distress
다소간 손상이 올 수가 있지만
and some damage to her vocal chords,
환자분 뇌에 손상이
오는 것보단 낫습니다
but better that than
damage to your brain tissue,
그건 회복도 안 됩니다
which can't be repaired.
안돼요, 학교 선생님이라고요
That can't happen. She's a schoolteacher.
- 목소리가 재산이에요!
- 걱정하시는 바를 알지만
- She needs her voice!
- Craig, we respect your concern, sir,
위험을 감수하셔야 돼요
but you need to know the stakes here.
If you have significant brain damage,
더구나 뇌 손상을
심각하게 입는다면
you may not come out of this.
병원문을 걸어서 못 나갑니다
Craig, you need to hear me.
크레이그 씨
제 말 좀 들어주세요
There are no great options here.
이게 최선이에요
There are going to be
risks no matter what we do.
어떤 방법을 취하더라도
모두 위험성이 있습니다
Now, you need to let go and trust us.
저희를 믿고 맡겨주세요
We have more ways to help
her if she gets into trouble
아내분께선 문제가 생겨도
저희가 도울 방법이 있지만
than if you do.
환자분은 아니에요
I'll take that risk.
위험을 감수할 겁니다
No, Mary!
안돼, 메리
If something happens to
you, I don't care if I live.
자기한테 문제가 생기면
사는 게 무슨 의미야
I won't let them cut if it hurts you!
자기한테 안 좋다면
쇠막대를 안 자를 거야!
- [Monitor beeping rapidly]
- Hey, you need to stop moving!
환자분, 그만 좀 움직이세요!
Sats are down to 90!
산소포화도 90입니다!
What's going on? What's beeping?
무슨 일이에요
이 소리는 또 뭐죠?
The airway's filling with blood!
혈액으로 질식하겠어!
- Give me the...
- [Speaks indistinctly]
간호사...
Joey: His moving dislodged the blood clot!
남편이 붙잡고 흔들면서
혈전이 떨어져나갔어!
Tell me what's going on!
무슨 일인지 말해주세요!
They need to be separated!
I'm cutting the rebar.
당장 분리해야됩니다
쇠막대는 제가 자르겠습니다
- No, Mary!
- Hand me the bone saw, please.
- 정신 차려, 메리!
- 뼈톱 좀 주세요
Tell me what's happening!
무슨 일인지 말해달라고요!
Discussion over. She needs a trach now.
얘기 끝입니다
당장 기관절개 해야돼
Krista, prep the neck.
크리스타, 준비해줘
- [Sobbing] No...
- I need steriles.
- 안돼...
- 소독해주세요
[Rapid beeping continues]
Topher, we're shorthanded out here.
토퍼 선생님, 급성 뇌졸중 환자가
내원했는데 일손이 부족해요
I need you to see an acute stoke patient.
- When it rains, it pours, right?
- Krista, you're up.
- 설상가상이네
- 크리스타, 대신 들어가
Okay, I'm on it.
- Okay, suction.
- Help her! Help her! Mary!
알겠습니다, 선생님
- 석션해줘요
- 메리 좀 살려주세요!
- All right, stabilize him.
- Oh, my God, help her, please!
- 환자 좀 잡아요!
- 제발 살려주세요!
- Here we go.
- Mary!
- 시작합니다
- 메리!
- [Whirring]
- Aah!
[Whirring fades]
[Phone rings]
[Ringing continues]
[Clatters]
[Rings]
Michael Ragosa.
라고사입니다
안녕하세요, 클라크 씨
Yes, yes, Mr. Clark. I was just, uh,
부탁 하신대로
통계를 내고 있었습니다
working on those numbers for you.
새로운 의무조항에 대해선
논의 중이고
And the new insurance mandate.
And the medicare and medicaid
reimbursement projections.
저소득층 의료보험제도의
보험금 환급방안은 궁리 중입니다
I'm all over it.
맡겨주십시오
Okay.
알겠습니다
이만 끊겠습니다
Okay. Thank you. Bye-bye.
Well, I don't want to be a bother.
남 성가시게 하는 거
질색인데
그냥 목이 좀 아픈 거야
재향군인국에 접수해놓고
It's just a sore neck thing,
but I've been waiting for, like,
three months for an
appointment from the V.A.
한창 기다리던 중이었는 걸
All right, Tricia, stop. Just... it's done.
트리샤, 불편해하지 마
Go hang in the waiting
room, and I'll set it up.
대기실에서 기다려
잘 말해놓을 테니까
- 여깄었네
- 애는?
- Hey, T?
- Yeah?
- 상태가 좋아
- 잘됐다
- Kid's doing better.
- Oh, great.
Listen, could you make sure to
see my friend Tricia tonight?
내 친구인데 시간나면
진료 좀 봐줄 수 있어?
She's a big help to me in therapy group.
상담치료할 때
많이 도와줬거든
- 이렇게라도 도와주고 싶어
- 해줄게, 그런데 조심해
- I want to help her out.
- Yeah, of course, but we got to be careful now.
Ragosa's back. He finds out
라고사가 복귀했어
- 몰래 치료하는 거 들키면 끝장나
- 알지
- we're doing this off-book, we're done.
- Yeah.
Okay? [Laughs] It's not...
- 맞지?
- 아냐
- Sure!
- No, it's exactly how...
- 아니긴!
- 어떻게 된 거냐면...
- 여긴 웬일이야?
- 오랜만이네
- T.C.
- Gwen.
May I have a word, Dr. Alexander?
알렉산더 선생님
드릴 말씀이 있는데요
- Sure.
- Mm-hmm.
- 해보시죠
- 잠깐만...
I like it when you stop by.
자기 올 때만 기다렸어
- 오늘은 환자를 데리고 온 건데
- 그렇겠지
- Well, actually, I have to bring in a patient.
- Mm.
자기 보러 온 것처럼
But I could go out and come back in
- 다시 나갔다 올까?
- 말이라도 고맙네요
and pretend like I came
here to see you, if you like.
- [Laughs] Yeah, okay.
- Hey, T.C. What's up, man?
웬일이세요, 선배님?
잘 지내시죠?
- Hey, Paul. Hey.
- Hey. Okay. Good to see you, man.
- 반가워, 폴
- 좋아보이세요, 선배님
- Yeah.
- So, working on the vets.
- 그래?
- 요즘 수의사 꼬시고 있어요
Uh, mum's the word on that one.
아무한테도 말하시면 안돼요
Um, it's a bit busy,
but I got it, so... Cool.
많이 바쁘긴 한데
이해해야죠... 예쁘거든요
That's great. Can you make
sure to see my friend Tricia?
잘됐네, 저기 내 친구가
왔는데 좀 봐줄래?
- Yeah.
- See you around, buddy.
- 물론이죠
- 그럼 나중에 보자고
선배님, 우리 새로운
휴게실 어떠세요?
So, uh, what do you think
of the new break room, right?
You wanna... you wanna maybe
play some pool after the shift?
근무 끝나고...
당구나 한 게임 하실래요?
- I'm pretty good.
- You know what, Paul?
- 제가 좀 치거든요
- 저기, 폴 선생?
Maybe you should get a start on those vets.
수의사한테 얼굴이라도
한번 더 비춰봐
- Yeah, like now, even.
- Topher: Hey, uh, Jordan?
- 그래, 이럴 시간에
- 저기, 조든?
A little help, s'il vous plaît,
의사들 일정 정리하는
일 좀 도와줄래?
with the doctors' schedule.
- Not so good with the paperwork.
- Right.
- 서류작업 정말 못하더라
- 그렇군
He's been doing this for
weeks. Okay. Don't leave.
몇 주째 저래
가지말고 있어
No.
안 가
So, just so you know, T.C.,
티시, 명심해
if you hurt her again,
조든한테 한번만 더
상처를 주면
you're gonna have to deal with me.
죽을 줄 알아
Ah, easy, Gwennie. I'm not gonna hurt her.
진정해, 그웬
이젠 안 그래
- Mm-hmm.
- No.
- 그러셔야지
- 안 그래
It's not like last time when
I came back from the war.
전쟁터에서 막 돌아왔던
그때같지 않아
You know it's different now.
알면서 그래
I'm taking it... slow.
- 천천히 시작할거야
- 줘봐
Like I said, hurt her,
그건 알 바 아니고
상처만 입혀봐
그 날로 죽는다
and you're dealing with me.
Hey, Topher, I just got a
call from the courthouse.
과장님, 법원에서
연락이 왔는데요
Some type of major crush injury?
중증압궤상을 입은
부상자가 있대요
They said they can't
move him and he's critical
이송할 수 없는데다
환자 상태가 심각하고
- 의사가 필요하답니다
- 이 케이스 좀 맡아줘
- and needs a doctor.
- Jordan, you take this.
- On it.
- All right, Gwen, we're up.
- 그러지 뭐
- 그웬, 같이 가자
Catch you later?
이따 봐
Hey, Mollie.
우리 예쁜 간호사님
Um, where exactly was that crash injury?
어디서 벌어진 거래요?
승강기에 갇혔는데
Guy got stuck in the elevator,
조치가 늦어지니까
겁이 났는지
panicked about being late for something,
강제로 열려고 했나봐요
and tried to squeeze out.
그러다 갑자기
승강기가 움직이면서...
That's when the elevator moved and...
누가 좀 살려주세요, 제발요!
somebody save him! Help, please!
- 아빠 좀 살려주세요!
- 알았어, 최선을 다해볼게
- You've got to...
- Okay, okay, I'm gonna do my best.
He's my dad!
[Crying]
세상에
[Thud, all gasp] Oh! Whoa!
가서 우리 애들 좀 더 불러와!
Paramedic: Let's go! We need more support!
뭐라도 받쳐놔야 돼!
Shore it up! Shore it up!
- You better work fast.
- Yeah.
- 빨리 조치를 취해야겠는데
- 그니까
[Sobbing]
케이블을 차단해서
승강기를 멈춰야겠어!
Man: Block the cable so it doesn't move!
메리는 어때요?
How's she doing?
Looking good. I'm incising the trachea.
좋습니다, 기관을 절개합니다
I'm ready with the trach tube.
튜브 준비하고 있어
Okay.
삽관하세요
Tube's in.
관 삽입합니다
Inflating the balloon.
풍선을 부풀리겠습니다
All right. The bleeding has stopped.
출혈이 멈췄습니다
Virtual fist bumps all around.
하이파이브 하죠
Thank you, Doctors.
감사합니다, 선생님들
Now that we've got her airway secured,
기도가 무리없이 확보됐으니
we can safely remove the
rebar from both of you.
두 분께 박힌 쇠막대를
안전히 제거할 수 있습니다
There's a neurosurgeon
waiting for you up in O.R. 1,
환자분은 1번 방에서
신경외과의가 집도할 거고
바로 옆방에선
저희가 아내분을
and we're gonna take care of your wife
- 수술할 겁니다
- 감사합니다, 선생님
- in O.R. 2 right next door.
- Thank you, Doctor.
You should stretch in between surgeries.
짬날 때마다
스트레칭도 하고 그래요
- Be good for you.
- All right.
- 꽤 쏠쏠하답니다
- 알겠습니다
- You should try it.
- You ready, Mr. Woo?
- 진짜 한번 해봐요
- 환자분, 준비되셨죠?
- Yeah.
- All right.
됐습니다
There's a loud friction rub.
심장막 마찰음이 커
- He's bleeding around his heart.
- Okay.
- 심장 주위에 출혈이 있어
- 이 사람이군
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐해?
She was sent out on a
major crush case alone.
중증 압궤상 부상자인데
혼자 파견됐잖아
I thought Jordan could use
the help of a good samaritan.
착한 사마리아인의 도움이
필요할 것 같아서
More like a good adrenaline junkie.
그보단 착한 흥분상태 중독자에 가깝지
I could definitely use the help.
도움 준다면야 사양 안할게
Okay, look, this poor man
is having labored breathing.
지금 이 부상자는
호흡이 가빠
He needs his airway stabilized,
호흡을 안정시켜야 하는데
but I can't intubate him in this position.
이 자세로는
삽관을 할 수가 없어
We have to go nasotracheal.
비기도로 삽관해야겠어
I've done it a dozen times
before on the battlefield
전쟁터에서 많이 해봤어
when a soldier can't be
moved. Best way to intubate.
일반적인 삽관이 어려울 때
이만한 방법이 없지
Gwen, can you hand me
a 6.0 endotracheal tube?
그웬, 6mm 기관내관
좀 갔다 줄래?
I'll place a nasal airway for dilation.
비기도 확보하고 있을게
Can I also get some
blankets here to prop him up?
환자를 받칠 담요 좀
갔다주실래요?
[Groaning] We're gonna
take care of you, sir.
선생님, 저희들이
구해드릴 겁니다
- It's gonna be okay.
- [Sirens wailing]
마음 편히 먹으세요
- 뭐해요?
- 깜짝이야
Hey! Oh!
How's it going tonight?
오늘 근무는 어때요?
Well, you know what they say...
잘 아시겠지만...
30%는 지루하고
30%는 평범하다가
a third of the time boring,
a third of the time regular,
나머지 시간은 미쳐 돌아가죠
- a third of the time crazy.
- Ah, I see Jordan's got the crush injury
조든은 현장에서
압궤부상 환자를 보고 있고
선생님은 뇌졸중 환자를
보고 있네요
on site, you just saw a stroke patient,
드류는 목 아픈 환자를
보고 있고요
and Drew is taking care of a sore throat.
There something I can
help you with, Michael?
뭐 도와드려요?
아뇨, 일 보세요
No. Carry on.
[Pats back]
저, 사실 말입니다
선생만 괜찮다면
Well, actually, actually, uh,
if it's all right with you,
오늘은 여기서
시간을 보내고 싶은데
I thought I'd hang out down here tonight.
- Here?
- Yeah. You know,
- 여기서요?
- 나 말이죠
아파보니까
많은 걸 알겠더라고요
I learned a lot about
being a patient myself.
I realized I spent too much
time silo'd up in my office.
사무실에서만
갇혀 지냈더라고요
I need to be in the ebb and flow.
변화를 주고 싶어요
Get my hands dirty, you know?
손에 때 묻혀가면서요
I need to be more involved.
같이 발 벗고 뛰고 싶네요
All night, every night?
근무시간 때마다 매번요?
선생 일에는 관여 안할거예요
I'll stay out of your way.
I promise.
진짜예요
저...
- I...
- [Pats back]
How's it going?
오늘 근무 어떠세요?
Okay. All right, all
the Jacks are in place.
기중기들을 배치했어
Okay, listen up. Nobody does a thing
여기 알렉산더 선생님께서
- 신호를 주기 전까진 가만히 있어
- 예
- until Dr. Alexander gives the signal, okay?
- Mm-hmm.
선생님의 신호에 집중해
You only look at and listen to her, got it?
- All right.
- Yeah, okay.
- 알겠습니다
- 좋습니다
Okay, guys, on my count,
제가 셋을 세면
one crank at a time, okay? Understood?
동시에 올리는 겁니다
아셨죠?
- Tee, are you ready?
- Yeah, let's do it.
- 티, 준비됐어?
- 응, 해보자
Okay, good. On my count.
시작할게요, 셋을 셉니다
하나, 둘, 셋
1, 2, 3.
[Jack whirs]
Again.
다시 갑니다
하나, 둘, 셋
1, 2, 3.
[Jack whirs]
- He's bleeding out. We're losing him.
- His temperature's crashing.
- 출혈이 심해, 환자가 죽겠어
- 체온이 떨어지고 있어
- Lower the jack now!
- [All screaming]
- 기중기 내리라고요!
- 내려요, 빨리 내려요!
No! Daddy! Get it down! Now!
- 아빠, 안돼!
- 당장 내리라고요!
'오후 9시 3분'
♪
제작/저작권 : NBC
Airdated : 2015.2.23.
5~8화 감상은 올레TV로
더 나이트 쉬프트
시즌2 1화
회복
승강기가 오히려
환자를 살리는 형국이네
It's crazy, but the elevator
is keeping him alive.
Its weight is stopping him
from bleeding internally.
승강기가 짓누르면서
출혈을 막고 있어
He most definitely has severe
injuries to his heart and aorta.
심장과 대동맥에
큰 손상을 입은거야
Exactly. So if we move him, he dies.
맞아, 빼내려다간
오히려 죽겠지
But if he stays, he dies.
안 빼내도
죽는 건 마찬가지지만
- What he needs is E.C.M.O.
- We can't do that.
- 에크모 밖에 없어
- 어떻게?
E.C.M.O.'s never done
outside of a hospital.
병원 밖에서는
에크모가 안되잖아
Just because it hasn't been done
그야 그동안 해보질 않았으니까
doesn't mean that it shouldn't be.
Okay, look, if he has no blood in his body,
들어봐, 환자의 체내에
혈액이 없다면
then he cannot bleed out
when we move the elevator.
승강기를 들어올려도
출혈로 죽지 않을테고
We got at least 30 minutes
to get him to the O.R.,
응급실로 이송해서
부상을 치료할 시간을
repair his injuries.
30분은 벌 수 있어
I mean, E.C.M.O.'s his only chance, right?
에크모 밖엔 방법이 없다고
Even if we get approval,
and that is a huge...
승인을 받는다고 해도
이건 너무...
It's still better than if we don't try.
손 놓고 있는 것보단 낫잖아
[Exhales sharply]
- Let's do it.
- Okay.
- 까짓거 해보자
- 좋아
전화해볼게
Make the call.
Look at that. Heart rate's coming down.
정상동율동으로
점차 회복하고 있네요
He's got color in his cheeks. Looking good.
혈색도 돌아왔고요
좋아보인다
You got Ancef and Gent
for the open fracture?
개방성 골절에 세파스포린과
겐타마이신을 쓴 거죠?
- Uh, yeah. That's right.
- Ah.
- 그렇습니다
- 아하
Mira...
[Speaking Spanish]
[Continues in Spanish]
- Excuse me. Topher?
- Yeah?
- 토퍼 선생님?
- 무슨 일 있어?
조든 선생님께서 전화하셨어요
It's Jordan calling from the scene.
She needs to speak with you right away.
당장 좀 바꿔달라시는데요
- Thank you, Ken.
- Yeah.
알았어
All right, later.
이따 보자
[Siren wailing]
무슨 일이야?
What's up, Jordan?
E.C.M.O.? In the field? Are you nuts?
에크모를 현장에서?
미쳤어?
- Ragosa will never approve that.
- Just pass me through to Ragosa.
- 라고사가 거부할거야
- 라고사한테 얘기나 넣어봐
Well, he's... he's right here.
그게... 여기 있어
Hey, Michael, it's Jordan.
실장님, 조든 선생이 찾아요
What's going on?
무슨 일입니까?
일단 얘기부터 들어요
Okay, before you say
no, I need you to listen.
Michael, you know that I
lost my father at a young age.
제가 어릴 때 아버지를
여읜 거 아시죠?
Your kids almost lost you.
실장님 자녀분들도
그럴 뻔했고요
Scott, would you mind
if I put on some music?
선생님, 음악 틀어도 되겠습니까?
I like it when I suture. I, uh,
봉합할 때 듣곤 하는데
find it activate sensory pathways
감각신경을 활성화시켜서
that compete with pain
pathways, reduces anxiety,
통증에 대항한답니다
불안감도 감소시키고요
- all sorts of good things.
- Ah, I'm not really a music guy in the O.R.
- 그 외에도 많은 장점이 있어요
- 글쎄, 내 취향은 아니군
- Some other time.
- All right, let's get this rebar out of here right now.
- 한번 해보세요
- 이제 쇠막대를 빼내보지
And... It's...
드디어...
Out.
빠졌군
Beautiful.
깔끔하네요
No bleeding.
출혈도 없고
Needle driver and 5.0 Vicryl to me, please.
니들 드라이버와
5.0 봉합사 주세요
- Close her out...
- Dr. Clemens, sorry to interrupt.
이제 봉합을...
클레멘스 선생님
수술 중에 죄송합니다
- Jordan needs to speak with you.
- I'm a little busy right now.
- 조든 선생님께서 바꿔달라십니다
- 지금 바쁘다고 전해요
They're taking an E.C.M.O.
unit out in the field
현장에 에크모를
가져가는 중이고
and they need a surgeon.
외과의가 필요하시대요
- What?
- Never heard of that before.
- 뭐라고요?
- 이런 경우는 없었잖아요
- Ragosa approve this?
- It's already being loaded.
- 실장님이 승인했어요?
- 이미 싣고 있다는데요
Go ahead, Scott. I just gotta close.
가보세요, 선생님
제가 봉합할게요
Krista can be my second set of hands.
크리스타 선생이
어시를 볼 수 있을 겁니다
If they're going to do that,
you need to be out there.
에크모를 가져갈 정도면
현장에는 선생님이 필요해요
Son of a bitch.
이런 망할
Jocelyn, could you please
page Dr. Bell-Hart for me?
간호사, 벨하트 선생님 좀
호출해주실래요?
- Sure.
- And, uh, go ahead
알겠습니다
가는 길에 음악도 켜주세요
- and turn on the music, please?
- Thanks.
감사합니다
- [Beep]
- [Soul music playing]
Man: ♪ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ listen ♪
[Suction whooshing]
No, you get two pills four
times a day, that's it.
안돼, 이미 하루에 4회씩
2알 먹고 있잖아
Rick, you can't take any
more. It's not good for you.
릭, 더는 처방 못해줘
몸에 안 좋다고
I know... I'll see you in the morning.
알지... 아침에 봐
Sorry it's taking so long,
오래 기다리게 해서 죄송합니다
but I swear you're gonna be next.
다음 차례에는
진짜로 보실 겁니다
진찰 받으려고
몇 달도 기다려봤는데
Oh, I've waited for months to see a doc,
몇 시간 정도는 껌이죠
so a couple hours is nothing.
의사한테 음료와 감자칩을
받는 호사도 누리는데요
Plus I never had a doc get
me soda and chips before.
Oh, hey. Where... where
you going with that?
케니, 그거 들고
어디 가는거야?
Oh, uh, Paul needed some
extra supplies for the vets.
폴이 수의사 가져다 준다고
남는 집기가 필요하대요
So... Yeah. Oh, nice, good.
아... 잘됐네
- Um, hey, I've been meaning to ask you a question.
- What's up?
- 계속 못 물어봤는데
- 뭔데요?
How long have you been
sleeping with Krista?
크리스타와 언제부터
그렇고 그런 사이가 됐어?
[Laughing] What are you talking...
농담도...
- I'm not sleeping...
- Dude, I've been in the closet for 20 years.
- 아무 사이도 아니...
- 반평생을 베일 속에서 살아왔어
- 무슨 소리인지...
- 숨기는 게 있으면 딱 감이 와
- What are you talking...
- I know when someone's keeping a secret.
Plus, I saw you two at
the Riverwalk on Friday.
금요일에 리버워크에서
같이 있는 걸 보기도 했고
Okay. Okay.
이것 참
[Lowered voice] But you can't tell anybody.
아무한테도 얘기하지 마세요
- Just a hookup, or...
- You can't...
- 그냥 가벼운 관계야, 아니면...
- 진짜 비밀인데...
그게 어쩌다 보니까
그렇게 됐는데...
well, it started off like
that, man, but I don't know.
I mean, it feels like...
그니까 뭐랄까...
feels like it's turning
into something else now, man.
다른 감정이 생기기
시작하는 것 같아요
[Air horn blows]
[Snorts] And you said
Paul sent you in here?
아까 폴이 보냈다고
하지 않았어?
Oh...
이런...
That young'un's gonna pay.
어디 가만두나 봐라
폴 조심해야겠네
[Chuckles] Paul better watch out.
[Sneezes]
[Siren wailing in distance]
- Where are they?
- Let me deal with him. You'll just piss him off.
이 인간들 어딨어?
자긴 가만히 있어
사람 화부터 돋구니까
[Police radio chatter]
What the hell are you doing?
도대체 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
And what is T.C. doing here?
He's still under suspension.
저 인간은 또 뭐하는 건데?
정직 상태잖아
Okay, let's just focus
on this man, all right?
일단 부상자한테
집중하자, 응?
종격동 부상이 심한데
압박으로 인해 탐폰이 생기고 있어
Pressure is tamponading
severe mediastinal injuries.
Yes. The E.C.M.O. is a hail mary,
에크모가 최후의 수단이야
but we have to try. We
can't just let him die here.
시도라도 해봐야지
여기서 죽게둘 순 없잖아
누군 죽게 두고 싶대?
I don't want him to die
here, but you just said it.
말 잘했네
최후의 수단이란게 뭐야
It is a hail mary, and if you
try it and it doesn't work,
일이 잘못되면
당신과 병원을
you're putting yourself and the hospital
정조준해서 소송을 걸거라고
in the cross-hair for a lawsuit.
Still doesn't mean it shouldn't be done.
그런 건 이유가 못 돼
승강기 통로에서
심혈관을 우회한다는 거잖아!
It's cardiac bypass in an elevator shaft!
- [Clattering]
- Hey, hold... hold, hold, hold, hold.
잠깐만... 잠깐만 기다려주세요
Jordan, listen to me, okay?
조든, 내 말 좀 들어줘
Because you didn't listen
to me last time with Milo,
저번 마일로 때 기억나잖아
and he ended up dead, and
you were under investigation.
총격범이 죽으면서
괜한 수사를 받았잖아
No, this has nothing to do with Milo.
마일로 얘기가 왜 나오는 건데?
No, it has everything to do with it.
정말 몰라서 묻는 소리야?
지금처럼 자기 판단을
앞세워 나쁜 결정을...
It has to do with your judgment,
and the bad decisions that...
hey, hey, hey! What the hell is going on?
지금 뭐하는 겁니까?
Okay, look. You need... you need to listen.
일단... 내 말부터 들어요
To you? Last time I saw you,
수술방에서
신경쇠약이 온
you were having a nervous
breakdown in my O.R.
사람의 말을
내가 왜 들어야 하는데?
It was so bad they had to suspend you,
얼마나 심각했으면
정직처분까지 내렸을까
- so I don't even know what you're doing here right now.
- Scott...
- 그 장본인이 여기서 뭐하는 겁니까?
- 스캇...
No, no, no. No. No. Go ahead, let it out.
괜찮아, 말리지마
계속 말해봐요
Say whatever you want, 'cause I
don't care what you think of me.
당신이 뭐라 떠들던
신경 안써
Okay? But just 'cause
you're pissed off at Jordan
조든 선생한테
상처를 받았다고
'cause you got your feelings hurt,
화풀이를 하는 거라면
you're gonna let that man die?
저 부상자도 죽게 둘 겁니까?
No, I'm not letting anyone die.
누가 죽게 내버려둔답니까?
- I am pointing out that if you move that guy...
- Point it out later!
- 상관으로서 두 사람이 에크모를...
- 상관 노릇은 나중에 하라고!
Okay, look. I hate saying this,
이런 말 하기는 싫은데
but right now you are the only one
지금 저 사람을 살릴 사람은
who can save that man.
당신 밖에 없어
They need you.
선생이 필요하다고
Okay, but if we do this, we do it my way.
좋아, 대신 한다면
제 방법대로 할 겁니다
You understand? You do
everything that I say,
지시에 따라주세요
because that is his
only chance. You got it?
유일한 방법이니까요
Sure. Whatever you need.
알겠습니다, 뭐든 하시죠
Everybody listen up.
여러분
We're going to do a veno-arterial bypass.
정맥-동맥 에크모를 할 겁니다
I don't have access to his heart or groin,
심장과 서혜부로는
접근을 못하니
so I'm going in through the neck.
경정맥을 경유할 겁니다
We need cooled saline and
bags of ice... lots of them.
냉각된 식염수와
얼음이 많이 필요합니다
I need the venous and the arterial circuits
정맥과 동맥 회로선을
직접 연결할 겁니다
flushed and ready to go.
준비해주세요
- Let's get started.
- Okay. Come on.
- 시작합시다
- 나 좀 도와줘
Scott: All right, let's save this guy.
'오후 10시 31분'
작동되네. 부상자의 뇌물질대사의
속도를 늦춰야 돼
It's working. We need to slow
down his brain metabolism.
- More ice.
- Looks like that's it.
- 얼음 더 갔다주세요
- 그만하면 됐어요
Blood is drained.
혈액을 뺐습니다
심부 온도는 16.5도를
유지해주시고
Core temp's holding at 16.5.
30분 안에 수술을 못하면
조직이 괴사할 겁니다
We got 30 minutes to
get him through the O.R.
Or tissue starts to die.
- 가망이 없으신거죠?
- 그거야 모르지
- He's not gonna make it, is he?
- We don't know that.
없는 말로라도
제 마음을 달래보시라고요
No, you're just saying
that to make me feel better.
저 아니면 법원에
오실 필요도 없었어요
But he wouldn't have even
been here if it wasn't for me.
과속 딱지는 머저리같이
왜 받아서...
I got this stupid speeding ticket, and...
아빠는 못 보내요
I can't lose my father. [Breath quavers]
제 전부라고요
He's all that I have.
알리샤, 언니가 약속할게
Alicia, I promise you
최선을 다해볼게
that we are going to do
everything that we can.
저기 계신 선생님은
제일 가는 외과의셔
Dr. Clemens is our top surgeon.
- So right now, I-I just need you to be strong.
- [Exhales]
심지를 굳건히 했으면 좋겠어
That's what they said when my mom died.
엄마가 돌아가실 때도
의사가 그렇게 말했어요
굳건히 하는 것도 신물나요
I'm so tired of being strong.
Scott: All right, people,
got to move. Let's go!
여러분, 끝났습니다
빨리 이송합시다!
끝났나 봐, 우리도 일어서자
Okay, honey, we got to go now, all right?
[Alicia sighs]
You were a captain? I was just a grunt.
대위셨습니까?
전 일개 졸병이었는데
다 같은 동료입니다
Nah, there's no such thing as a grunt.
손 좀 주세요
티시 선배가 그러는데
Give me your hands. Anyway, T.C. told me
전공을 혁혁하게
세우셨다는군요
how kick-ass you were out in the field,
그에 맞춰 응당한
대우를 해드리는 겁니다
so we're gonna give you
the A-plus treatment.
미시고
Push. Pull.
당겨보세요
바이코딘은
언제부터 복용하셨나요?
Now how long you been on the Vicodin?
몇 달 됐습니다
다른 약은 잘 안 듣거든요
Months. It's the only thing that helps.
통증을 차단해야
훈련을 하니까요
Truth is, I need them to
block the pain so I can train.
I want to re-enlist. I want
to learn to fly choppers.
재입대를 위해
헬기조종을 배우려고요
U.A.E의 여성 전투기 조종사처럼
I want to kick some I.S.I.S. ass
다에시 놈들을
쓸어버리고 싶거든요
like that woman fighter
pilot from the U.A.E.
- 힘이 되는 얘기네요
- 그런데 통증이 발목을 잡네요
- I like the sound of it.
- Yeah, but the pain keeps me from training.
I won't pass the physical. I
can barely do three push-ups.
체력테스트를 통과 못할 거예요
푸쉬업을 세 개도 못하거든요
가슴까지 턱을
당겨보시겠어요?
Can you put your chin to your chest?
- 테스트를 통과해야되니까...
- 고개를 올려보세요
- So I just need to pass the test...
- Head up.
돈도 아낄 겸 통증 고치러
지압사한테 가보려고요
Save the money, and get a
chiropractor to fix my neck.
끝났습니다
- All right.
- [Coughing deeply]
- [Coughing, wheezing]
Okay. Yep. Ma'am.
여기 휴지 있습니다
혹시 물 필요하시면...
Do you need some water, or...
[Coughing]
전에도 이러신 적 있나요?
Uh, has this happened before?
- 몇 번요
- 일단 앉아계세요
- A couple times.
- Okay. Relax.
폴, 흉부 CT 찍어봐야겠어
Paul, we're gonna need a chest C.T.
- 은밀히 해야되는 거 알지?
- 물론이죠
- Remember, it's off-book.
- Okay.
Uh...
저희가...
We'll get to the bottom of this.
원인을 알아낼 겁니다
회복실로 데려가주세요
Joey: Let's get her to recovery.
신경검사는 도착해서 바로 하고
하루동안은 2시간마다 해주세요
Check a neuro exam on arrival
then "Q" two hours overnight.
목에 쇠막대가 박힌
환자는 처음이시죠?
So I take it that was your
first rebar in the neck, too?
처음이죠
담장기둥, 부러진 하키채나
Yeah. Seen fence posts,
broken hockey sticks,
날붙이나 유탄발사기에
당한 건 봤지만
swords, knives, R.P.G.
수류탄이요?
군대에 계셨어요?
Grenade? You were in the military?
공군 사관학교
99년 졸업생이랍니다
Yes, ma'am. Air Force
academy, class of 1999.
No offense, but you
don't seem like that type.
비아냥대는 게 아니라
그렇게는 안 봤거든요
[Scoffs] And what type is that?
어떻게 보셨는데요?
요가나 엔야의 노래를
좋아하시니까
You're just more of a yoga-quoting,
싸움을 말리시는
타입으로 보였거든요
- Enya-listening, meditating type.
- [Chuckles]
싸우는 것도 보셨겠네요?
Did you see any action?
이라크에 파병갔을 때
몇 번 봤어요
Yeah. A couple of tours in Iraq.
Yeah, Drew was in Iraq, too, as a medic.
드류 선배도 의무병으로
이라크에서 복무하셨는데
I think half our shift
served in the military.
여긴 군인 출신이
반 이상 되는 것 같아요
그러면 선생님도
여기 배치받으셔서
So, I mean, were you just stationed here
and you decided to stay
like most everyone else?
다른 선생님들처럼
눌러 앉으신거예요?
아뇨, 플로리다 토박이인데
No, I'm a local boy.
환자들 보려고
좀 전에 왔습니다
Just came back from Florida
to take care of my parents.
God, that is sweet. You
must really love them.
멋지세요, 지금 일을
정말 사랑하시나봐요
[Siren wailing] Not really.
글쎄요
- 비켜주세요, 수술방 잡아놔요!
- 괴사를 막으려면 당장
- Everybody move! Let's make some room!
- We have to start the rewarming
- 체온을 높여야 됩니다!
- 병원은 우리 관할이니
- right away, or his brain will die!
- You have to stay out of it now!
손 떼요!
We're back in the hospital. Tell the O.R.
가자마자 바로 개흉할 겁니다!
We're cracking his chest
the second we get up there!
정중 흉골 절개술 한다고
확실히 말해주세요
Make sure they know I'm
doing a median sternotomy.
- 알겠습니다!
- 조심해서 올라갑시다
- I got it!
-Let's go, let's go, let's go. Steady.
Have Dr. Chavez meet me there.
차베스 선생 오라고 해요
[Exhales deeply]
Gotta say, when I first saw the elevator
이제와 말하지만
승강기에 깔린 걸
on this guy's chest, I didn't
expect him to make it this far.
봤을 때 이렇게 오랫동안
버틸 줄은 몰랐어
Yeah. That was a good call by Jordan.
조든 선생님이
처치를 잘하셨어요
Ballsy. This guy had no other option.
과감하셨지만
다른 방법이 없었잖아요
So, dual rebar operation and an E.C.M.O.
쇠막대에 관통된 부부부터
에크모까지
That's a hell of a first night for you.
첫날부터 고생이군
Piece of cake compared to my first night
알 안바르 주로 파병나간
첫날에 비하면
in Al-Anbar province.
별 것도 아닙니다
자살테러범이
시장으로 들어왔어요
Suicide bomber walked into a market.
We heard the blast from 5 miles out.
5마일 밖인데도
폭발음을 들렸죠
Just... Never seen so many body parts.
조각난 시신들이...
사방에 널려있었어요
Just everywhere. Stuck to the walls.
Sorry, man. I had no idea.
그런 일이 있는 줄 몰랐어
No, don't be sorry. I
mean, how could you know?
별걸 다 죄송해 하세요
어떻게 아셨겠어요?
I hadn't thought about that in years.
한동안 생각 안하고 살았는데
So, no music in the O.R.
음악을 안 트시더라고요
I find it too much of a distraction.
너무 산만한 건 질색이라서
그러시군요
That's cool.
[Humming]
[Laughs] Just messin' with you.
괜히 말씀드렸네요
[Chuckles]
[Tricia coughing]
트리샤, 몇 분만 참아주세요
Oh, Tricia. Just a few
more minutes, darling.
Hang in there, okay?
- Oh. That's not good.
- [Coughing]
이런, 안 좋은데?
Hey. I just got word Tricia needed a scan.
트리샤가 CT 찍으러
갔대서 와봤어
What's going on?
뭔데 그래?
Son of a bitch. [Sighs]
젠장
종양이라고?
- A tumor?
- It's a stage 2 pancoast tumor at the top of
폐 상부에
2기 팬코스트 종양이 생겼어
your lung. That's what's
been causing your neck pain,
근육결림이 없이
목이 아팠던
- not a pulled muscle.
- No way. I don't smoke.
- 원인으로 보여
- 어떻게? 담배도 안 피는데
I swear, I've never smoked.
정말로 담배 안핀다니까
If someone's smoking, I walk away.
누가 담배 피면
저만치 비켜섰다니까
아프간 임무 당시에
폐기물 적치장에서
I saw one of your duties in Afghanistan
임무를 수행하셨더군요
was working in the trash pits.
You were exposed to all sorts of chemicals
그 과정 중에서
온갖 화학물질에
- for hours every day.
- They said it was safe.
- 노출된 거 같네요
- 부대에선 괜찮댔어요
- 죄송합니다
- 이제 어떻게 해야돼요?
- I'm sorry.
- What do I do?
We get it out of there.
어떻게든 해결해볼게
Don't B.S. me, T.C.
헛소리 할 생각마
You know I'm a straight shooter.
말 돌리는 사람 싫어해
누군 아니래
So am I.
우리한테 맡겨줘
We're gonna take care of you, okay?
Promise.
약속할게
I shouldn't have to take 15 phone calls
그 놈의 에크모는
왜 현장에 파견시켜서
in the middle of the night
오밤 중에 전화에
시달리게 만듭니까?
because you approve an
E.C.M.O. in the field!
- Wait. It needed to be done.
- I don't even know what to say.
- 필요한 조치였습니다
- 기가 차서 말도 안 나오네
Do you have any idea how much that costs?
비용이 얼마나 드는 지 아세요?
Yes.
압니다
그걸 아는 사람이 승인해요?
And yet you did it anyway!
What the hell is wrong with you?
도대체 뭐가 문제입니까?
왜 승인한 거냐고요!
Why the hell would you do that?
이유나 들어봅시다
I'm waiting.
I did it because, um...
그만두기 전에...
I wanted to do... [Exhales]
이 자리에서...
one decent thing on this job
보람찬 일을 한번만이라도
before I quit.
해보고 싶었거든요
- You're quitting?
- Yeah.
- 그만둔다고요?
- 그렇습니다
I quit.
그만둡니다
I don't want to do this job anymore.
이따위 짓거리 하기 싫습니다
I had a piece of my brain removed
종양을 제거하려고
뇌조직 일부를 떼어냈습니다
to get to my tumor.
Most people can barely recite
the alphabet after that,
대부분은 수술 뒤에
정상 생활이 힘들다던데
멀쩡하게 돌아왔으니
욕만 들어먹는 이 자리를
but I have all of my faculties,
and I refuse to push paper
at a place where everybody hates me!
계속 맡을 이유가
없단 말입니다!
Ahh! God, this feels so good.
이렇게나 기분이 좋다니!
[Inhales sharply]
벼르던 일을
마침내 끝냈을 때
You have no idea how good it feels
그 기분을 알 턱이 없으시겠죠
to finally do what you want to do.
So, yes.
다시 한번 말합니다
Yes. I quit.
그만둘 겁니다
And I could not be happier.
더할 나위없이 기쁩니다
- 아침까지 책상 치워요
- 이미 치웠어요
- Have your desk cleaned out by morning.
- I already started.
- [Staff murmuring]
- Man: Ragosa's quitting.
실장님이 그만둔대
말도 안돼
Man: Oh, that's crazy.
'오전 1시 31분'
Hey, you.
알리샤, 너니?
The nurses said that I would find you here.
여기 있을 거라더니
정말 있네
My dad always hated this stuff.
아빠는 제 모습에 질색하셨죠
But he never said anything.
하지만 내색하지 않으셨어요
He just let me be me.
절 믿고 기다리신거죠
좋은 소식을 가지고 왔어
Well, I have some good news.
I just spoke with the O.R.,
수술 담당 선생님과 얘기했는데
and so far your dad's holding up.
아빠 상태가 좋대
Thank you. [Exhales]
감사합니다
I called my aunt from
Dallas. She's coming down.
달라스 고모한테 연락했더니
지금 오시는 중이래요
- Good. That's good.
- Yeah.
- 다행이네
- 그러게요
Alicia, I want to apologize to you
알리샤, 아까 언니가 그랬잖아
for what I said earlier.
마음 단단히 먹으라고
About being strong.
그 말 사과할게
- Oh, I...
- No, I don't even know why I said that to you,
- 아뇨, 제가...
- 나도 왜 그랬나 모르겠다
because I always hated it
when adults said that to me.
어른들이 그 말 할 때가
제일 싫었어
왜 마음을 굳게 먹고
No, I never understood
why I had to be strong,
왜 울면 안되고
why I couldn't cry,
왜 감정은 사치인지
이해가 안됐거든
why I couldn't have feelings.
Feelings are good, Alicia.
감정은 느끼라고 있는 거야
Don't ever let anyone tell you how to feel.
아무도 이래라저래라
할 수 없어
I don't know how I feel.
무슨 기분인지 모르겠어요
I'm just numb.
그냥 멍해요
Well, uh, do you mind if I...
너만 괜찮다면...
Stay with you until your aunt gets here?
고모님이 오실 때까지
같이 놀래?
You know, maybe we could be numb together.
같이 멍이나 때리지 뭐
[Laughing, crying]
같이 울어도 되고
뭐든 괜찮아
Or cry. I'm... [sighs]
I'm cool with whatever.
[Laughs] Uh...
주책이에요
[Olivia Broadfield's "Gone" playing]
- [Sighs]
- ♪ and I'm leaving ♪
[Sniffles]
♪ And your storm ♪
- It's gonna be all right.
- ♪ Keeps on raging ♪
괜찮으실 거야
[Mouths word]
Okay.
정리해보면
So she can't get into the V.A. for months
일이 밀려서 재향군인국에
because of the backlog.
몇 달 못 갔는데
At which time her cancer
will be stage 3 or 4,
암이 3기나 4기였다면
꼼짝없이 죽을 뻔했지
too late for her survive.
Pentagon buys $200 million
planes that nobody wants,
국방부는 비행기 사냐고
2천억씩 꼴아박는데
- 군인은 의사 하나 못 구하네요
- 그랬다더라
- but a soldier can't get a doctor.
- Topher: Yeah, I hear that.
And she has no insurance and no savings,
보험은 커녕
저축해놓은 것도 없으니
so she can't get a surgeon to do it.
의사한테 수술도 못 받겠지
다른 환자들처럼 여기서
검사하면 안돼요?
Why don't we just check her
in here like everybody else?
I mean, get her tests done
on-book and just do it here.
정식으로 검사하고
여기서 수술해버려요
We have a great thoracic surgeon on staff.
우리 병원에 실력 좋은
선생님들 많잖아요
Yeah, and we have to
treat everybody who comes
우리는 들어오는 족족
치료할 의무가 있지만
수술전담의는 예외야
through those doors. Surgeons don't.
They just treat emergencies.
물론 긴급할 때는 하지만
- This is an emergency.
- Not technically.
- 긴급상황이잖아요
- 정확히는 아냐
뭐... 곧 그렇게 되겠지만
I mean, it... it will become one.
Okay, let's at least do what Paul says.
모르겠다, 폴 말처럼
시도라도 해보자
Let's check her in. Get
it... get it started.
수술전담의한테 가서
설명이라도 해볼래
Let's present the case to the surgeon.
혹시 해줄지 알아?
Who knows? Maybe he'll do it.
Are you planning your escape?
어디가려고?
그럴까 생각중이야
Ha. Yeah,
토퍼가 병원 안에서
얼쩡거리지 말래
Topher thought it was better
if I wasn't hanging
out inside the hospital.
Suspension and all. [Chuckles]
정직 당한 애가
뭐하냐고 하네
- Ah, yeah. That little thing.
- Mm-hmm.
- 난 또. 별일인가했네
- 별일은
[Sighs] It's a weird shift, huh?
오늘 정말 이상한 날이야
You know, E.C.M.O. and
the motorcycle accident.
에크모도 그렇고
오토바이 사고도 그렇고
That is why I never let you on my bike.
오토바이에 안 태우는
이유를 알겠지?
Well, it was a pretty amazing
thing to witness, you know?
나 오늘 정말 놀라운
광경을 목격한거 있지
I mean, this guy has a piece
of rebar through his brain,
뇌에 철제봉이
박힌 환자가 들어왔는데
and the only thing he can
think about is his wife.
오로지 자기 아내
안부만 묻더라
Well, guess if you find the right woman,
이 사람이다 싶은
반려자를 만나봐
you'll do anything for her.
자기도 뭐든 하게 될걸
[Cell phone vibrates]
[Sighs and groans]
Topher wants me back
inside. It's about Tricia.
토퍼가 잠깐 들어오래
트리샤 일이라는데
Yeah, I heard about that.
얘기 들었어
I'm sorry, T, that's... that's really sad.
유감이야
하늘도 정말 무심하다
You know, I never... Told
you how great she was for me.
얼마나 나한테 잘해줬는지
얘기를... 안 했을거야
I didn't wanna burden you with my therapy.
나 치료 받는 얘기 꺼내면
짐만 되는 것 같아서
You're not a burden.
짐은 무슨
Yeah, just... I need to
get there myself, you know?
이건 뭐... 스스로
해결해야되는 문제니까
But, uh, she's a real ball buster for me.
트리샤가 나 때문에
고생을 많이 했어
She was the first one to call me out.
처음으로 날 찾아준
사람이거든
Oh, yeah?
그랬어?
- Yeah.
- How?
- 응
- 뭐랬는데?
Well, she was like,
보통 이런 식이었지
'사지로 걸어들어간 건 형이네'
"your brother got himself killed,"
'본인이 판단을
잘못 내려서 전사한거네'
and that Thad dying
was his fault, not mine,
but... That he was reckless
and he had no business
'사람이 너무 부주의하네
의무병이라지만'
'엄연히 장교인데
먼저 투입시키는 게 어딨어'
sending a doc in there first...
that was an N.C.O.'s job...
and that he put the entire platoon at risk
'의무병을 먼저 보냈다가'
by putting the medical
officer in jeopardy. [Exhales]
'죽으면 남은 소대원들은
어쩌라는 거야'
- 주옥같은 말인데
- 거기 있는 사람 다 동의하더라
- Wow.
- The entire group completely agreed with her.
자기 생각이 중요하지
But did you agree with her?
[Flaps lips] You know, if it wasn't me,
글쎄, 다른 상황이라면
I probably would have, but, uh...
분명 쐈을거야, 그런데...
You know, it's hard to look at it that way.
생각을 달리 하기가
너무 힘들어
You shouldn't be so hard on yourself, T.
너무 자책하지마
- Yeah. And...
- And you've changed.
- 알지만...
- 자기는 확실히 달라졌어
I've seen it.
내가 알아
When I had my breakdown...
다시 무너졌을 때 말야...
변화의 계기가 됐지
breakthrough.
Yeah. Uh...
뭐, 아무튼...
You know, you said you would always
항상 곁에 있어주겠다는
약속을... 지켜줬잖아
be there for me, and... and you have.
I just wanted to say that
that meant a lot to me.
큰 힘이 됐다고
말하고 싶었어
[Cell phone vibrates]
Gotta...
이것 참...
- Guess we should go back inside.
- Yeah.
- 들어가야겠다
- 그러게
Don't make any plans for
two weeks from Friday.
2주 뒤 금요일에
시간 비워놔
Why?
왜?
Tee, why?
뭐하려고?
[Sighs]
Hey, I spoke
티, 흉부외과의와
to the thoracic surgeon about Tricia.
트리샤 수술 건으로
얘기 나눠봤거든
It's a no-go.
안된댄다
He can't do one pro Bono surgery?
프로보노 수술 하나 못해준대?
Actually, he does several each month.
안 그래도 매달 몇 건씩 하거든
He can only do so many.
더는 못한대
He did say he'd cut his fee in half,
대신 비용을 50% 깎아서
1,700만원이면
so all we need is 15 grand. You got that?
가능하다는데, 돈 있어?
What do you think?
있을 것 같아?
That was a rhetorical question.
말하는 거 보니 알겠네
I'd be surprised if you had 15 bucks.
있다고 했으면 놀랄 뻔 했어
[Sighs]
- 어쩔 수가 없다
- 아냐
- I'm sorry, brother.
- Yeah.
Excuse me, ma'am?
잠깐만 실례하겠습니다
남편분과 같은 병실을
쓰고 싶어하실 것 같더라고요
We thought you might wanna
share the room with your husband?
He should just be coming, too.
모셔오는 중입니다
[Mouths words]
마음만 받을게요
Don't even try.
재수가 없었다고
얘기하고 싶을거야
[Under breath] Talk about beating the odds.
아내분, 쇠막대의 남은 부분을
제거하려고
Ma'am, we needed to sedate
your husband to pull the last
불가피하게 진정제를
투여했습니다
of the rebar out.
쇠막대가 움직이면서
통증이 심했거든요
It had shifted, and the
pain was just too intense.
Mr. Woo, can you hear us?
환자분, 저희 목소리 들리세요?
Remember me? I'm Dr. Zia.
지아 선생인데, 기억나시죠?
I worked on you when you came in. Mr. Woo?
옆에서 같이 일했잖아요
You're here with your wife.
She's right next to you, sir.
아내 분이 바로 옆에 계세요
환자분, 아내분께
할 말 없으세요?
Mr. Woo? Do you wanna
say anything to your wife?
[Speaks Asian language]
환자분, 영어로
말씀해주셔야 합니다
Mr. Woo? I need you to
speak to me in English.
[Continues speaking Asian language]
못할 거예요
I don't think he can.
'오후 6시 34분'
She says her husband grew
up in a bilingual family.
아내분 말론 남편이
이중언어 가정에서 자랐다네요
That explains it.
그러면 설명이 되죠
I was able to preserve his speech,
언어중추를 손상시키지 않았지만
but the rebar must have injured
쇠막대가
2차 언어를 처리하는
the English language centers of his brain.
영역을 손상시켰나 봅니다
처음부터 다시 배워야할 겁니다
He's gonna have to completely relearn it.
쇠막대가
Well, considering that
시속 70마일의 속도로
머리를 관통한 걸 생각하면
a pole went through his
brain at 70 miles per hour,
I think things can be
a hell of a lot worse.
이만하면 다행이죠
Okay. Here we go. I downloaded
a Mandarin-to-English app,
그래서 광둥어-영어
통역앱을 받아왔어요
and I figured... that way you could talk,
이제 서로 대화하시고
저희가 설명도 드릴 수 있어요
- and we could explain.
- That's a great idea, Krista.
- 저희가 설명드릴 수도 있을 겁니다
- 좋은 생각인데
Mandarin-to-English.
Who knew?
광둥어-영어 통역기라니
I'm gonna send the Cantonese
version to my parents.
부모님한테 보내봐야겠는데?
[Dizzy X's "Walking in the
sun (Acoustic)" Playing]
[Chuckles]
말도 안돼, 어떻게 된 거야?
I'm in shock. I don't understand.
I thought you said the surgeon couldn't.
수술을 못한다고
말할 줄 알았거든
I know, but he got an
opening in his schedule.
그랬는데, 그 선생님의
수술 스케줄이 비었어
There's a certain amount
of pro bono cases per month,
매달 프로보노 수술로
할당된 양이 있는데
and one fell through, and
it's just lucky timing.
마침 하나가 계획이 틀어졌거든
하늘이 도운거지
[Laughs] Oh, my God!
말도 안돼!
You were up next.
대신 네가 들어가게 됐어
이런 일도 생기는 구나, 고마워!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Thank you.
[Kisses]
Huh? Oh.
무슨 일이에요?
- Did you hear?
- What?
- 들으셨어요?
- 뭘요?
The surgeon agreed to
do it. I'm gonna live.
의사가 제 수술을 해주겠대요
저 살았어요!
I'm gonna live!
살았다고요!
♪ I'm gonna walk in the sun tomorrow ♪
♪ I'm gonna get me to ♪
♪ All my... ♪
Core temp's back up to 98 degrees.
심부 온도를 36도까지 올렸어
So far, so good.
현재까진 경과가 좋습니다
How's it going? How's our E.C.M.O. patient?
에크모 환자는 어때?
You're just in time
for the moment of truth.
결정적인 순간에
딱 맞춰왔네
Let's come off bypass.
바이패스를 분리하겠습니다
Coming off bypass.
바이패스를 끄겠습니다
[Whoosh, monitor emits continuous tone]
[Beeping rapidly]
심장박동이 없어
It's not beating.
너무 오래 쉬었군
디프브릴레이터 주세요
It just needs to wake
up. Give me the paddles.
- [Beeping continues]
- Clear.
클리어
[Defibrillator whines, thump,
monitor emits continuous tone]
[Whispers] Come on, come on.
Increase the joules to 20.
- 제발 뛰어라
- 20줄까지 높여주세요
Clear.
클리어
[Defibrillator whines, thump]
- [Beeping steadily]
- Okay, sats are rising.
산소포화도가 올라가고 있습니다
Come on, take it to the rack, baby.
심장아, 이젠 뛰어볼 차례야
[Steady beeping continues]
All right. You did it, Scott.
됐어요, 선생님
해내셨어요
That was amazing. Really amazing.
정말 대단했어
Okay, I'm gonna disconnect the tube.
이제 관을 제거하겠습니다
Scott?
스캇?
I'm really sorry about how
things turned out between us.
우리 사이를 이렇게
만든거 정말 미안해
Yeah. Well, you got what you wanted.
당신만 행복하다면 됐어
Okay, let's close.
좋아요, 봉합합시다
♪ All my sorrow ♪
Hey, Drew, honey, come here.
드류 선생님, 잠깐만요
Will you help me with this, please?
이것 좀 도와주실래요?
I gotta get it straight,
and I can't get it up.
똑바로 붙여야 되는데
잘 안돼요
Just, will you hold that?
잠깐만 잡아주세요
Yeah, yeah.
잠깐만 기다려요
Just put it up a little bit higher.
조금만 더 올려주실래요?
Right there. That's... you know what?
거기요, 거기 딱 좋네요
That's perfect right there.
딱 적당한 자리예요
- You need to...
- [Laughs] That's perfect.
- 이제...
- 그렇지
Okay, come on, come on.
빨리 돌아, 빨리 돌라고
Finally got you.
드디어 잡았네요
오래 기다렸네
도대체 어디있었어요?
[Speaks indistinctly] Sucker.
Huh? Where you at? [Laughs]
Dr. Chavez, come here.
You've got to see this.
차베스 선생님
이것 좀 와서 보세요
- What the hell, guys?
- [Laughter]
도대체 뭐야, 두 사람?
Excuse me? Ken?
지나가야 되니까 비켜줄래
- 켄?
- 숨은 쉬게 해줘야지
[Laughter] Let me help you breathe here.
That's amazing. That is amazing.
여러분들 진짜 환장하겠네요
We're just one big happy
family, right, Drew?
선생님, 우리 완전
화목해보이죠?
Yeah, I can see that.
진짜 그렇게 보여요
I think I'm gonna like working
here. You guys are crazy.
앞으로 재밌게 일하겠는데요
여러분 완전 골때리네요
- Welcome to the night shift, Dr. Chavez.
- Don't touch me.
- 차베스 선생님, 환영합니다
- 건드리면 죽는다
건드리면 죽는다고 말하네요
He said, "don't touch me."
- Are you serious?
- [Singsongy] Sandwiches.
- 진짜 이러기야?
- 치즈
[Laughter]
[Head thudding]
Uh, you... you okay?
어, 저기... 괜찮으세요?
No, I am not okay. I made
a huge, massive mistake.
괜찮긴 뭐가 괜찮아요
제대로 미친 짓을 저질렀잖아요
You see these... these big speeches
막 영화 같은데서
거창한 연설을 보면
in the movies, and it looks cool,
완전 멋있어보이고
and the guy gets the girl and the job,
배경음이 쫙 깔리면서
주인공은 일과 사랑을
모두 얻죠
and the music plays?
그런데... 아무 일도 없잖아요
배경음은 개뿔
Well... That ain't
happening. There is no music.
망했어, 완전 망했다고!
뭔 짓을 저지른 거지?
I am so, so screwed! What
the hell was I thinking?
Clearly, you had some
things to get off your chest.
가슴에 맺힌 울화가
많으셨던 것 같던데
I-I-I couldn't have waited, huh?
선수 친 겁니다
He was... he was 30
seconds away from firing me.
날 당장이라도
자를 것 같잖아요
I would have had a-a severance package,
퇴직금이라도 챙기고
I would have had C.O.B.R.A. insurance.
코브라 보험이라도 들어놓을 걸
Do you have any idea
how much insurance costs
한 가구가 보험료로 1년에
for a year for a family?
얼마나 지출하는 지 알아요?
Absolutely. About 20 grand.
약 2,300만원 정도잖아요
You know we don't get insurance here.
여기 직원은
보험 못 들잖아요
So what are you gonna do?
이제 어떻게 하실 요량이세요?
Actually, I'm gonna...
계획이 있긴 한데...
I've been studying to take the boards
의사 면허를 따려고 한창...
and get my M.D.
공부하고 있는 중이에요
개방성 골절을 치료하는 법을
어떻게 아시나 했더니
That is why you knew how
to treat the open fracture.
정말 좋은 결정을 내리셨어요
[Chuckles] I was gonna say...
Well, good for you. You
know, I was in residency
50대 변호사와
같이 산 적이 있는데
with a 50-year-old lawyer
who changed careers.
그 분도 뒤늦게
직업을 바꾸셨죠
It's never too late.
절대 안 늦었어요
You know one thing I
learned from almost dying?
죽을 뻔했던 일로부터
제가 배운 게 있다면요
You have to live in the moment.
현재를 살아야 한다는 거예요
That is the best that we can do.
우리가 할 수 있는
최선의 일이니까요
결례를 범하지 않았길 바랍니다
I hope I didn't make
a huge mistake tonight.
Because right now it
really feels like I did.
폐를 끼쳤다는 느낌이
팍팍 들거든요
Hmm. You got a second?
I wanna show you something.
잠깐 시간 되시죠?
보여주고 싶은게 있습니다
Come on.
와보세요
See what's going on in that room?
이 방에서 무슨 일이
있었는 지 아시죠?
That's because of you.
모두 당신 덕분이에요
That girl has her father back
당신이 저 소녀의 품에...
- because of you.
- [Sighs]
아버지를 다시 안겨줬어요
Doesn't feel like a huge mistake to me.
그러니 결례를 범했단
생각은 접으세요
Thanks, Topher.
고마워요
Y-you know, um...
아시나 모르겠는데
It's about an 80% pay cut,
uh, but we have an opening
임금이 대폭 삭감되면서
보조의사 자리에
for a physician's assistant.
결원이 생겼거든요
Now you know what it is.
무슨 일인지는 아실 거예요
일상적인 업무에
서류작업은 산더미고
It's a lot of scut work, lot of paperwork,
자존심 죽이는 일도 많겠죠
lot of... ego humbling,
but if you really wanna pass your boards
하지만 정말 자격 시험을 통과해서
and be a doctor, there's
no better way to learn.
의사가 되고 싶으면
배우기에 이만한 자리도 없어요
[Laughs] A physician's assistant?
보조의사 자리요?
Yeah, and with your med
school, you more than qualify.
당신이 다닌 의대면
자격은 넘치죠
생각이나... 해보시라고요
So... just... just think about it,
and if you hate it, you can always quit.
싫으면 언제든
그만두셔도 되고요
Right?
괜찮죠?
God knows you already got the speech down.
말문이 막힐 때도 있네요
이 분를 구하셨다니
믿을 수가 없네요
I can't believe you guys saved him.
그 선생님하고 얘기했는데
I talked to the surgeon.
He said you gave him the $15k to pay
트리샤의 수술비로
1,700만원을 줬다면서?
for Tricia's operation.
Oh, yeah?
그렇게 말해?
And then Kenny said he
saw your bookie riding off
케니가 봤는데
네 마권업자가 구형 할리를
끌고가는 걸 봤다네?
on your old Harley.
Selling Thad's old bike.
형의 오토바이를 판 거야?
[Clicks Tth] That was an
unbelievably amazing thing
그런 일까지 하다니
케니한테 듣고도
못 믿었다니까
you did for her, T.
나한테 빌린 90만원을
갚을 적당한 때가...
Of course, now if you
wanna pay me back the $800
that you owe me...
[Chuckles] Yeah.
팔았어
I don't know, man.
근데 모르겠다
I learned I need to let some of Thad go.
형의 물건들을
보내야 된다고 그러더라
내 자신을 알고
You know? Figure out what's me
and what's me trying to be like him.
형의 그늘에서
벗어나려면
You know?
무슨 얘긴지 알지?
알지
Yeah. I do know.
나와 트리샤 둘 다
비운에서 벗어나는데
I thought maybe this could help both of us
도움이 되겠지 싶어서
move on from a bad hand.
I hope it does. I love you, brother.
그러길 바래
너를 왜 싫어하겠니
I love you, too.
마찬가지야
그나저나 90만원은
적선했다고 생각해
But you are never getting
that $800 back. [Groans]
Why... why does that not surprise me?
네가... 그럼 그렇지
토퍼, 티시 선생님
와서 이것 좀 보세요
Hey, Topher. T.C.? Hey,
you guys need to see this.
Hey.
괜찮니?
티시 선생님, 감사합니다
Gracias, T.C.
천만에
[Whispers] De nada.
What's going on?
뭘 보라는 건데?
그웬 씨가 선배와 조든의
옛 모습이 담긴 영상을 올렸어요
Gwen uploaded a video of you
and Jordan from back in the day.
2007년 할로윈 파티 때
기억나지?
Halloween at our apartment, 2007. Remember?
Oh. Oh, God. [Laughter]
이런, 세상에
이걸로 화면보호기 바꿔야겠는데?
Topher: I just found my new screen saver.
- 헐마이어니 양, 각선미 죽이네요
- 잠깐, 잠깐만
- Nice legs, Hermione. Nice legs.
- Oh, okay, okay.
Not Hermione. Her-man-ee. You know?
헐마이어니가 아니라
헐매니야
And Jordan is Harry Paw-ter.
Like the paws on the tie.
조든은 해리 포우-터인데
넥타이에 새긴 발자국 알지?
The costume shop was
very specific about that.
코스튬 가게 주인이
장황하게 설명하더라고
[Laughter] I think he looks
younger than I do, maybe.
지금의 저보다도
어릴 때 같은데요
여러분, 한번 더 돌려볼까요?
All right, one more time from the top.
얘가 지금, 두고 봐
No. All right, revenge is swift.
티시가 이 표를
어떻게 구한거야?
How in the hell did
T.C. score those tickets?
뭔 소리야, 무슨 표?
What tickets? What are you talking about?
2주 뒤 금요일에
스파이스 걸스 공연 앞좌석 표
The Spice Girls, front
row, two weeks from Friday,
2장을 줬다고!
you and me?
- Are you serious?
- [Whispers] Yes!
- 진짜로?
- 그렇다니까!
Unbelievable.
이런 일도 다있네
[Laughter]
그 표들은 어떻게 구한거야?
So how did you score those tickets?
몇 달 전에 매진된건데
They were sold out months ago.
스파이스 걸스 좋아하는 거 알고
몇 달 전에 구해놨어
Yeah? I got 'em months
ago. I knew you liked them.
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
[Button clacks]
♪♪
I thought you wanted to take it slow.
천천히 시작하고
싶은 줄 알았는데
I lied.
거짓말이야
♪♪
- synced and corrected by OussLP -
- www.addic7ed.com -